<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://singhaman1750.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://singhaman1750.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-02T13:05:07+00:00</updated><id>https://singhaman1750.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aman Singh</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Planetary Gearbox - How to Calculate Gear-ratio?</title><link href="https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2026/how_to_calculate_the_gear_ratio_of_a_planetary_gear_system/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Planetary Gearbox - How to Calculate Gear-ratio?"/><published>2026-01-28T10:32:20+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-28T10:32:20+00:00</updated><id>https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2026/how_to_calculate_the_gear_ratio_of_a_planetary_gear_system</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2026/how_to_calculate_the_gear_ratio_of_a_planetary_gear_system/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Fig 1: Planetary gear system </div> <h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1> <p>Planetary gearboxes are one of the most widely used gearbox designs in mechanical engineering. They are extensively used in robotics, especially in the development of joint actuators for humanoid, quadruped, and other legged robots. The primary reasons for their widespread popularity are their low gearbox inertia and high efficiency, which make them ideal for robotic joint applications.</p> <p>Beyond robotics, planetary gear systems are widely used in the automotive industry, particularly in automatic transmissions. The versatility of planetary gearboxes is evident from the fact that they are used in mechanical systems ranging from large-scale applications such as airplanes and helicopters to compact devices like hand drills.</p> <p>The aim of this blog post is to derive the mathematical expression for the gear ratio (or gear reduction) of a planetary gear system as a function of key gear parameters such as the number of teeth and the module.</p> <h1 id="design-of-planetary-gearbox">Design of Planetary Gearbox</h1> <p>A planetary gearbox design mainly consists of four different parts, as shown in Fig. 1: the sun gear, the planet gear, the ring gear, and the carrier. The sun gear, ring gear, and carrier share a common fixed axis of rotation. The sun and planet gears are external gears, while the ring gear is an internal gear. Each planet gear meshes with the sun gear on one side and with the ring gear on the diametrically opposite side. The carrier is a link that connects the center of the sun gear to the center of the planet gear, and it has revolute joints at the centers of both the sun and planet gears.</p> <p>In a particular configuration, one of the sun gear, ring gear, or carrier is fixed with respect to the ground, one of the remaining components acts as the input, and the third acts as the output. For example, the sun gear can be fixed, the carrier can serve as the input, and the ring gear can be the output. However, the most commonly used configuration fixes the ring gear, applies the input at the sun gear, and takes the output from the carrier. This configuration is widely used because it provides the highest gear ratio (output torque to input torque ratio) for a given set of gear teeth. In this blog post, we derive the gear ratio for this specific configuration only.</p> <h1 id="gear-ratio-calculation">Gear ratio calculation</h1> <h2 id="module">Module</h2> <p>The module of a spur gear is calculated by dividing the Pitch circle diameter with the number of teeth of the gear. In a planetary gearbox, the module of the sun, the ring and the planet gear should be same in order to get proper meshing of the gears. The mathematical relation of the module, the diameter and the number of teeth of the gear is given as:</p> \[m = \frac{PCD}{N} = \frac{2R}{N}\] <p>Rearranging the above equation results in:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:module_relation} \frac{m}{2} N = R \end{equation}</p> <p>where $m$ is the module of a gear, $PCD$ is the Pitch circle diameter of the gear, $R$ is the radius of the gear, and $N$ is the number of teeth of the gear.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set_geometric_and_velocity_diagrams-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set_geometric_and_velocity_diagrams-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set_geometric_and_velocity_diagrams-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Planetary_gear_set_geometric_and_velocity_diagrams.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Fig 2: Planetary Gear System, (a) Geometric relation, (b) Velocity diagram </div> <h2 id="geometric-relation">Geometric relation</h2> <p>The geometry of the sun, planet and ring gear follow a relationship, see Fig 2 (a). The radius of the ring gear is equal to the sun of radius of sun gear and twice the radius of planet gear. This relation can be mathematically represented as follows:</p> \[R_{s} + 2 R_{p} = R_{r}\] <p>where $R_{s}$, $R_{p}$, and $R_{r}$ are the radii of the sun, planet and ring gears, respectively.</p> <p>From Eq.$\eqref{eq:module_relation}$, we can see that the Number of teeth of each gear is directly proportional to the radius of the gear. The constant $m/2$ has to be same for all the three (sun, planet and ring) gear, to ensure proper meshing. So, we can write that:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:geometric_relation} N_{s} + 2 N_{p} = N_{r} \end{equation}</p> <p>where $N_{s}$, $N_{p}$, and $N_{r}$ are the Number of teeth of sun, planet and ring gears, respectively.</p> <h2 id="velocity-equations">Velocity Equations</h2> <p>To calculate the gear ratio we will have to write the relation between the angular velocities of the sun gear, planet gear, and the carrier. To do that let’s look and the gear interaction points $A$, $B$ and $C$, see Fig 2(b). At point $A$ sun and planet gear are meshed together and at point $B$ planet and ring gear are meshed together. At point $C$, the carrier and planet gear are attached through a revolute joint.</p> <p>Meshing together can be looked as if the sun and planet gear move without slipping at point $A$, and planet gear moves without slipping (wrt fixed ring) at point $A$.</p> <p>Let’s assume that sun, planet, ring and carrier are rotating with angular velocities $\omega_{s}$, $\omega_{p}$, $\omega_{r}$, and $\omega_{c}$ in counter-clockwise (CCW) direction. Please note, $\omega_r = 0$ as ring gear is fixed. Also, let the velocity of the points $A$, $B$ and $C$ in Fig 2(b) be $V_{a}$, $V_{b}$ and $V_{c}$. The velocity of the centre of the planet gear, i.e. point $C$ in Fig. 2(b) can be given as follows:</p> \[V_{c} = - \omega_{c} R_c = - \omega_{c} (R_{s} + R_{p})\] <p>The negative sign shows that the velocity is in negative (left) direction.</p> <p>The velocity of sun gear particles at point $A$ is $V_{a}^{sun} = - \omega_{s} R_{s}$ and that of planet gear particles is $V_{a}^{planet} = V_{c} + \omega_{p} R_{p}$. Because, the sun and planet are meshed at $A$ these velocities should be equal. So, we get the following equation:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:velocity_balance_bw_sun_and_planet} (-\omega_{c} (R_{s} + R_{p})) + \omega_{p} R_{p} = - \omega_{s} R_{s} \end{equation}</p> <p>A similar thing can be done at point $B$. The velocity of planet gear particles at point $B$ is $V_{b}^{planet} = V_{c} - \omega_{p} R_{p}$ and that of ring gear particles is $V_{b}^{ring} = \omega_r R_{r} = 0$ as ring is fixed. Equating these two, we get:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:velocity_balance_bw_planet_and_ring} (- \omega_{c} (R_{s} + R_{p}) - \omega_{p} R_{p}) = 0 \end{equation}</p> <h2 id="solving-the-velocity-equations">Solving the Velocity equations</h2> <p>In the Eq.$\eqref{eq:velocity_balance_bw_sun_and_planet}$ and Eq.$\eqref{eq:velocity_balance_bw_planet_and_ring}$, $\omega_s$ (input velocity) and the radiis are the known values. The $\omega_{p}$ and $\omega_{c}$ are unknown values. We have a system of 2 equations with 2 variables. To solve the equations you can just add Eq.$\eqref{eq:velocity_balance_bw_sun_and_planet}$ and Eq.$\eqref{eq:velocity_balance_bw_planet_and_ring}$ to get the value of $\omega_{c}$ and subtract them to get $\omega_{p}$. The solution of the equations should look like the following:</p> \[\omega_{c} = \frac{R_{s}}{2(R_{s} + R_{p})} \omega_{s}\] \[\omega_{p} = \frac{R_{s}}{2R_{p}} \omega_{s}\] <p>Using the Eq.$\eqref{eq:module_relation}$ we can write the following:</p> \[\omega_{c} = \frac{N_{s}}{2(N_{s} + N_{p})} \omega_{s}\] \[\omega_{p} = \frac{N_{s}}{2N_{p}} \omega_{s}\] <p>Using the Eq.$\eqref{eq:geometric_relation}$ we can say that $2(N_{s} + N_{p}) = N_{s} + N_{r}$ and $2N_{p} = N_{r}-N_{s}$. Hence:</p> \[\omega_{c} = \frac{N_{s}}{(N_{s} + N_{r})} \omega_{s}\] \[\omega_{p} = \frac{N_{s}}{(N_{r}-N_{s})} \omega_{s}\] <p>The gear reduction can be given as: \begin{equation} \label{eq:gear_reduction} \frac{\omega_{c}}{\omega_{s}} = \frac{N_{s}}{(N_{s} + N_{r})} \end{equation}</p> <p>We can see that $N_{s} &lt; (N_{s} + N_{r})$, which means $\omega_{c} &lt; \omega_{s}$. So, the output angular velocity is less than the input velocity. This is why it called a gear “reducer”.</p> <h2 id="torque-relation">Torque Relation</h2> <p>In ideal no energy loss condition the input power to the gearbox should be equal to the output power. So:</p> \[\tau_{in} \omega_{in} = \tau_{out} \omega_{out}\] \[\tau_{s} \omega_{s} = \tau_{c} \omega_{c}\] <p>where $\tau_{s}$ and $\tau_{c}$ are torque input in sun and torque output from the carrier. The above equation can be written as:</p> \[\frac{\tau_{s}}{\tau_{c}} = \frac{\omega_{c}}{\omega_{s}} = \frac{N_{s}}{(N_{s} + N_{r})}\] <p>The gear-ratio ($GR$) can now be given as:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:gear_ratio} GR = \frac{\tau_{c}}{\tau_{s}} = \frac{(N_{s} + N_{r})}{N_{s}} = 1 + \frac{N_{r}}{N_{s}} \end{equation}</p> <p>The output torque value can be given as follows:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \label{eq:output_torque_relation} \tau_{c} = \large(1 + \frac{N_{r}}{N_{s}}\large) \tau_{s} \end{equation}</p> <p>We can observe the following points:</p> <ul> <li>We can see that as $N_{r} &gt; N_{s}$ the output torque is higher than the input torque.</li> <li>We can also see that the gear-ratio is independent of the module of the gears, it only depends on the number of teeth.</li> </ul> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>In this blog post we derived the gear-reduction ratio of the planetary gear system. We saw that the final gear ratio is independent of the module of the gears and only depends on the number of teeth of ring and sun gear.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="gears"/><category term="planetary_gear"/><category term="actuators"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fig 1: Planetary gear system]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Read a Research Paper - A PhD Researcher’s Guide</title><link href="https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2024/how_to_read_a_research_paper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Read a Research Paper - A PhD Researcher’s Guide"/><published>2024-10-12T22:00:20+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T22:00:20+00:00</updated><id>https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2024/how_to_read_a_research_paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2024/how_to_read_a_research_paper/"><![CDATA[<p>As a PhD researcher, reading research papers is an integral part of my daily routine. Not only does it keep me informed about developments in my field, but it also sparks new ideas and insights. However, when I first embarked on my research journey, I had a misguided notion about how to approach reading research papers. I believed that the best way to read a paper was to start from the beginning and push through to the end in one sitting, hoping to grasp every detail along the way. This approach proved to be highly unproductive and overwhelming.</p> <p>After discussing this challenge with fellow PhD students, one friend pointed me toward a YouTube video featuring Andrew Ng, a renowned expert in machine learning. His practical method for reading research papers was enlightening and has since transformed my approach. Below are the key phases of this method that can help you read research papers more effectively.</p> <h1 id="the-phases-of-reading-a-research-paper">The Phases of Reading a Research Paper</h1> <h2 id="phase-0-initial-assessment">Phase 0: Initial Assessment</h2> <p>In this phase, take a moment to read the <strong>title</strong> and <strong>keywords</strong> associated with the paper. This quick assessment helps you decide whether the paper is relevant to your interests or research area. If the title and keywords pique your curiosity, proceed to read further; if not, feel free to skip it. This step typically takes just <strong>1-2 minutes</strong> but is crucial for filtering out irrelevant papers.</p> <h2 id="phase-1-abstract-and-conclusion">Phase 1: Abstract and Conclusion</h2> <p>Once you’ve decided to read the paper, move on to the abstract and conclusion sections. These parts provide a concise overview of the paper’s motivation, main contributions, and results.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Abstract</strong>: This section summarizes the core ideas and findings of the paper.</li> <li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: Here, you’ll find reflections on the results and their implications.</li> <li><strong>Look for Diagrams</strong>: Sometimes one diagram or figure completely encapsulates the key concepts of the paper.</li> </ul> <p>After completing this phase, you should have a general understanding of whether you want to delve deeper into the paper.</p> <h2 id="phase-2-introduction-and-methodology">Phase 2: Introduction and Methodology</h2> <p>In this phase, read the introduction thoroughly while skimming through the methodology section.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Introduction</strong>: Focus on understanding the motivations behind the research, related works, and key contributions.</li> <li><strong>Methodology</strong>: You don’t need to grasp every equation or proof right away; instead, aim to understand the overall approach.</li> </ul> <p>If certain mathematical concepts or algorithms are clear to you at this stage, feel free to engage with them; otherwise, save them for later.</p> <h2 id="phase-3-detailed-examination">Phase 3: Detailed Examination</h2> <p>Now it’s time to dive deeper into the <strong>mathematical details, algorithms, and proofs</strong> presented in the paper. This phase may also involve running any available code associated with the paper if applicable. This detailed examination usually concludes your reading process for most papers. However, if you find yourself particularly intrigued or challenged by certain aspects, you may wish to continue your exploration.</p> <h2 id="phase-4-re-implementation">Phase 4: Re-implementation</h2> <p>In this final phase, consider <strong>re-implementing algorithms</strong> or <strong>working through proofs</strong> independently without referring back to the paper. This exercise can reveal gaps in your understanding or clarify concepts that initially seemed complex.</p> <p>While not all papers will require this level of engagement, it’s especially beneficial for those closely aligned with your own research. For instance, if there’s a proof that could be adapted for your work or an algorithm you aim to improve upon, this phase becomes invaluable.</p> <h2 id="practical-tips-for-effective-reading">Practical Tips for Effective Reading</h2> <ol> <li><strong>Use Phases 0 and 1 Wisely</strong>: These initial phases help you determine if a paper merits your time.</li> <li><strong>Expect Most Papers to End by Phase 2</strong>: In my experience, around 80-90% of papers can be comprehensively understood by this point.</li> <li><strong>Do not spend too much time in related works</strong>: Complete reading this paper first then the other papers it refers to.</li> <li><strong>Reserve Phases 3 and 4 for Relevant Papers</strong>: Focus on these phases when dealing with papers that are particularly pertinent to your current research.</li> <li><strong>Space Out Your Reading</strong>: Don’t feel pressured to complete all phases in one sitting. Consider breaking them up over several days for better retention.</li> </ol> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>I hope this article provides you with a clear framework for reading research papers more effectively. By breaking down your reading into manageable phases, you can enhance your comprehension while minimizing overwhelm.</p> <h2 id="credits--useful-links">Credits &amp; Useful Links</h2> <p>For further reading on effective research practices, consider checking out these resources:</p> <ul> <li>How to read a research paper by <em>Andrew NG</em>: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=733m6qBH-jI">Video</a> / <a href="https://github.com/IvLabs/ResearchPaperNotes/tree/master/literature_study_tips">Notes</a></li> <li>How to Read a Paper by <em>S. Keshav</em>: <a href="https://web.stanford.edu/class/ee384m/Handouts/HowtoReadPaper.pdf">PDF</a></li> <li>How to read a paper: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7044621048364900352?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop">LinkedIn Post</a></li> </ul> <h3 id="happy-reading">Happy reading!</h3>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="research"/><category term="research-paper"/><category term="reading"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2nd blog]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to write the Introduction of a research paper</title><link href="https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2024/how_to_write_the_introduction_of_a_paper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to write the Introduction of a research paper"/><published>2024-10-04T10:32:20+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T10:32:20+00:00</updated><id>https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2024/how_to_write_the_introduction_of_a_paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://singhaman1750.github.io/blog/2024/how_to_write_the_introduction_of_a_paper/"><![CDATA[<p>Writing a research paper can be a daunting task, and many researchers find the Introduction section to be the most challenging part. This section is crucial because it sets the stage for your research by explaining its significance, outlining the problem you are addressing, and distinguishing your work from existing solutions. Over time, I have developed a structured approach to writing the Introduction that helps make this process more manageable. Here’s a breakdown of that method.</p> <h1 id="structure-of-the-introduction">Structure of the Introduction</h1> <p>The Introduction should ideally consist of three main parts: Motivation, Related Work, and Contributions.</p> <h2 id="motivation">Motivation</h2> <p>In the Motivation section, articulate the reasons behind your research. Explain why this field of study is relevant and what specific problem you are addressing. This part should engage readers by highlighting the importance of your research and its potential impact. Consider incorporating narratives or real-world examples to illustrate your points effectively.</p> <h2 id="related-work">Related Work</h2> <p>The Related Work section should provide an overview of existing solutions that tackle similar problems. Discuss both the advantages and disadvantages of these approaches, highlighting gaps or limitations that your research aims to address. This critical analysis not only situates your work within the broader context but also serves as a foundation for justifying your contributions.</p> <h2 id="contributions">Contributions</h2> <p>In the Contributions section, clearly outline what makes your research novel, useful, and significant. List each contribution in a straightforward manner, ensuring that they are distinct and non-obvious. This clarity will help readers understand the value of your work and its relevance to the field.</p> <h2 id="optional-structure-overview">Optional: Structure Overview</h2> <p>As an optional fourth section, consider providing an overview of how your paper is structured. Briefly explain what each section contains and how they contribute to the overall argument or findings of your research.</p> <h1 id="integrating-sections">Integrating Sections</h1> <p>While you can treat these components as separate subsections, it’s often effective to weave them together into a continuous narrative. Each topic can be addressed in separate paragraphs, allowing for a smooth flow of ideas.</p> <h1 id="writing-tips-for-each-section">Writing Tips for Each Section</h1> <h2 id="motivation-1">Motivation</h2> <ol> <li><strong>Narratives</strong>: Explore various narratives within your field to create a compelling story.</li> <li><strong>Point Formation</strong>: List several key points that emphasize the significance of your research.</li> <li><strong>Editing</strong>: After drafting, review for grammatical accuracy and coherence.</li> <li><strong>AI Tools</strong>: Utilize AI tools like ChatGPT or Perplexity.ai to help rephrase or refine your paragraphs.</li> </ol> <h2 id="related-work-1">Related Work</h2> <ol> <li><strong>Preparation</strong>: Gather previous works relevant to your research area.</li> <li><strong>Advantages and Disadvantages</strong>: Create a list detailing both aspects of these papers.</li> <li><strong>Integration</strong>: Combine these points into a cohesive subsection.</li> <li><strong>AI Assistance</strong>: Again, leverage AI tools to enhance clarity and flow in your writing.</li> </ol> <h2 id="contributions-1">Contributions</h2> <ol> <li><strong>List Format</strong>: Clearly delineate each contribution as bullet points.</li> <li><strong>Main Statement</strong>: Synthesize these points into a comprehensive main research statement.</li> <li><strong>Rephrasing</strong>: Use AI tools to ensure clarity and precision in your contributions.</li> </ol> <h2 id="word-count-considerations">Word Count Considerations</h2> <p>The length of the Introduction can vary significantly depending on the type of publication you are targeting. For journal papers, it may be longer, while conference papers typically have shorter introductions. A good strategy is to review existing papers in your target publication—especially those in your field—and calculate an average word count for their introductions. For example, introductions in IEEE conferences related to robotics often range from 700 to 1000 words. In conclusion, following this structured approach will help you craft an effective Introduction for your research paper. I hope these insights prove helpful as you embark on writing your own introduction!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="research"/><category term="research-paper"/><category term="writing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing a research paper can be a daunting task, and many researchers find the Introduction section to be the most challenging part. This section is crucial because it sets the stage for your research by explaining its significance, outlining the problem you are addressing, and distinguishing your work from existing solutions. Over time, I have developed a structured approach to writing the Introduction that helps make this process more manageable. Here’s a breakdown of that method. Structure of the Introduction The Introduction should ideally consist of three main parts: Motivation, Related Work, and Contributions. Motivation In the Motivation section, articulate the reasons behind your research. Explain why this field of study is relevant and what specific problem you are addressing. This part should engage readers by highlighting the importance of your research and its potential impact. Consider incorporating narratives or real-world examples to illustrate your points effectively. Related Work The Related Work section should provide an overview of existing solutions that tackle similar problems. Discuss both the advantages and disadvantages of these approaches, highlighting gaps or limitations that your research aims to address. This critical analysis not only situates your work within the broader context but also serves as a foundation for justifying your contributions. Contributions In the Contributions section, clearly outline what makes your research novel, useful, and significant. List each contribution in a straightforward manner, ensuring that they are distinct and non-obvious. This clarity will help readers understand the value of your work and its relevance to the field. Optional: Structure Overview As an optional fourth section, consider providing an overview of how your paper is structured. Briefly explain what each section contains and how they contribute to the overall argument or findings of your research. Integrating Sections While you can treat these components as separate subsections, it’s often effective to weave them together into a continuous narrative. Each topic can be addressed in separate paragraphs, allowing for a smooth flow of ideas. Writing Tips for Each Section Motivation Narratives: Explore various narratives within your field to create a compelling story. Point Formation: List several key points that emphasize the significance of your research. Editing: After drafting, review for grammatical accuracy and coherence. AI Tools: Utilize AI tools like ChatGPT or Perplexity.ai to help rephrase or refine your paragraphs. Related Work Preparation: Gather previous works relevant to your research area. Advantages and Disadvantages: Create a list detailing both aspects of these papers. Integration: Combine these points into a cohesive subsection. AI Assistance: Again, leverage AI tools to enhance clarity and flow in your writing. Contributions List Format: Clearly delineate each contribution as bullet points. Main Statement: Synthesize these points into a comprehensive main research statement. Rephrasing: Use AI tools to ensure clarity and precision in your contributions. Word Count Considerations The length of the Introduction can vary significantly depending on the type of publication you are targeting. For journal papers, it may be longer, while conference papers typically have shorter introductions. A good strategy is to review existing papers in your target publication—especially those in your field—and calculate an average word count for their introductions. For example, introductions in IEEE conferences related to robotics often range from 700 to 1000 words. In conclusion, following this structured approach will help you craft an effective Introduction for your research paper. I hope these insights prove helpful as you embark on writing your own introduction!]]></summary></entry></feed>